Well, it seems that the first bucket is the best one,
似乎第一个桶是最佳选择
because no matter what we do,
因为无论我们怎么选
we'll always pick red, red,
我们总是能得到四个红色
red, red so we'll win every time.
因此 我们总是会赢
We can see that although it's not very easy to win in any of the other two,
我们发现尽管在剩下的两个桶中 要赢都不容易
it's easier to pick red,
但第二个桶中
red, red, blue in the second one,
更容易取到三红一蓝
and much harder to get red,
而在第三个桶中
red, blue, blue in the third one.
很难取到两红两蓝
Thus, the answers are: the best bucket is the first one,
因此 我们的答案是：第一个桶是最佳选择
the next one is okay,
第二个桶一般
and the third one is the worst.
而第三个桶最难
But by how much more specifically?
但具体相差多少呢
Let's ask the following question.
我们提出了下面的问题
What is the probability of winning in each of these games?
在这些游戏中 赢的概率有多大？
So, let's start by the easy one.
首先从最容易的开始
How likely is it to winning this game?
在第一个桶中 有多大概率赢得这场游戏
Well, to get the first ball to be red,
取到的第一个球是红色的概率
the probability is actually one.
为 1
Same thing for the second one,
第二 三 四个球是红色的概率
the third one, and the fourth one.
都是 1
Since we put the ball back after recording each color,
由于我们每次记录取出的球的颜色之后会将球放回
then these events are completely independent.
所以这些事件是完全独立的
So, the probability that they all occur is the product of the four probabilities.
因此 这些事件全部发生的概率是四个事件概率的积
This means the probability is one,
这也就是说 第一个桶的概率为 1
which matches our intuition that no matter what we do,
这和我们的直觉相符
we'll always pick red, red, red, red.
无论你怎么取 都会得到四个红色
Now let's go to the red,
现在来看第二个桶
red, red, blue case.
其中球的颜色为三红一蓝
What is the probability that the first ball we'd pick is red?
取出第一个球为红色的概率是多少？
Well, it's three over four or 0.75 since there are three red balls, and four in total.
是四分之三或 0.75 因为桶里的四个球有三个红的
Same thing for the second,
取出第二 三个球为红色的概率
and the third balls.
也是 0.75
Now what's the probability of the fourth ball we pick his blue?
那么 我们取出的第四个球为蓝色的概率为多少呢？
Well now it's one over four since there's only one blue ball among four.
是四分之一 因为四个球中只有一个蓝球
Therefore again, since the events are independent the probability
同样 这四个事件是独立事件
of the four of them happening is the product of the four probabilities,
所以所有事件全部发生的概率为其积
which is 0.75 times 0.75 times 0.75 times 0.25.
即 0.75 乘 0.75 乘 0.75 乘 0.25
This is 0.105 or around ten 10 percent probability of winning here.
答案是 0.105 也就是说 赢得这场游戏的概率大约是百分之十
And for the last one, well the chances here of getting a red ball are 50 percent,
在第三个桶中 共有两个红球和两个蓝球
since there are two red balls and two blue balls.
取出红球的概率为 0.5
And the chance of getting a blue ball are the same.
取出蓝球的概率也为 0.5
Thus, the chance of these balls being red, red, blue,
因此 此桶赢得这场游戏的概率
and blue is the product,
也为其积
which is 0.0625 or roughly six percent for winning in this game.
即 0.0625 或大约百分之六
We summarize these results in the table over here,
我们将这些结果总结在这张表格中
where the first column has a probability of a ball being red,
第一列表示取出的球为红色的概率
the second one off the ball being blue,
第二列表示取出的球为蓝色的概率
and the last one we highlight the probability of winning.
最后一列表示我们赢得这场游戏的概率
Now products are confusing mainly for two reasons.
现在这个结果可能会因为两个原因而令人费解
The first one is that if we have,
第一个问题是
say a a thousand balls.
假如我们有一千个球
Now, we take the product of a thousand numbers all between zero and one.
我们得到一千个球的积 这个积总位于零和一之间
This could be very tiny.
有可能非常小
The other reason is that a small change in one of
第二个原因是 稍微改变其中一个因素
the factors could drastically alter their product.
就会对最后的积产生极大的影响
We want something more manageable.
我们需要更可控的因素
And what's better than products?
还有什么比积更好呢？
Let's ask our friend here.
我们求助于我们的这位朋友
Yes, he is right.
他说得很对
Sums are better than products.
和比积好
And now we just need to turn the products into sums.
现在我们只需要将积改为和
Would any of the following functions be able to help us?
下面哪个函数更适用呢？
The options are sine,
我们提供的选项有
cosine, logarithm, or exponential.
sin cos log 和 exp
Enter your answer below.
请在下方输入你的答案